<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources xmlns:xliff="urn:oasis:names:tc:xliff:document:1.2">
    <string name="action_finish">Finish</string>
    <string name="action_next">Next</string>
    <string name="action_previous">Previous</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="boton_aceptar">Ok</string>
    <string name="boton_agregar_fraccion">Add fraction</string>
    <string name="boton_agregar_numero">Add number</string>
    <string name="boton_cai">C.T.I.</string>
    <string name="boton_cam">C.T.M.</string>
    <string name="boton_cancelar">Cancel</string>
    <string name="boton_equivalentes">Equivalent</string>
    <string name="boton_mayor">Largest</string>
    <string name="boton_mcd">G.C.D.</string>
    <string name="boton_mcm">L.C.M.</string>
    <string name="boton_reciprocas">Reciprocal</string>
    <string name="boton_rein">Res</string>
    <string name="boton_reiniciar_fraccion">Reset</string>
    <string name="boton_reiniciar_numeros">Reset numbers</string>
    <string name="boton_remover_fraccion">Remove</string>
    <string name="boton_simplificar">Simplify</string>
    <string name="CAL_MCD_IND">We will calculate the maximum common divisor (MCD) of the following numbers:</string>
    <string name="CAL_MCD_SX_EXP">The maximum common divisor (MCD) is the biggest number that a group of numbers is divisible by.</string>
    <string name="CAL_MCD_SX_INT">To calculate it, we have a test value that will start with 2, and we will divide all of the numbers by that test value, if the division of all of the numbers is exact, the test value will become a factor of the maximum common divisor (MCD).We continue testing with the same test value and when one of the divisions is not exact, then the test value increases to the next whole number and this same process is repeated. The calculation process ends when the test value becomes equal to one of the numbers.</string>
    <string name="CAL_MCD_SX_RES">The MCD is equal to the product of the factors that were found.</string>
    <string name="CAL_MCM_IND">We will calculate the least common multiple of the following numbers: </string>
    <string name="CAL_MCM_NX_RES">The lcm is:</string>
    <string name="CAL_MCM_SX_EXP">The least common multiple (lcm) is the smallest number that is divisible by a group of numbers.</string>
    <string name="CAL_MCM_SX_INT">To calculate it, we have test value that will start with 2, and we will divide all of the numbers by that test value. If the division of at least one of the numbers is exact, then the test value will become a factor of the least common multiple (lcm). We continue testing with the same test value and when none of the divisions is exact, then the test value increases to the next whole number and this same process is repeated. The calculation process ends when in the process of finding the factors of the lcm results in the original numbers becoming 1.</string>
    <string name="CAL_MCM_SX_RES">The lcm is equal to the product of the factors that were found.</string>
    <string name="calculadora">Calculator</string>
    <string name="desarrollado_por">Developed by: Porfirio Ángel Díaz Sánchez</string>
    <string name="DIV_SIM_NX">It is then solved with diagonal multiplications among the fractions:</string>
    <string name="DIV_SIM_SX">To resolve the division of two fractions, two diagonal multiplications of the 2 fractions have to be performed. The numerator of the final result is equal to the product of the numerator of the first fraction and the second fraction, and the denominator is equal to the product of the numerator of the second fraction by the denominator of the first.</string>
    <string name="DIVS_NX">The fractions are divided by pairs:</string>
    <string name="DIVS_SX">The division of more than 2 fractions is solved by grouping in pairs the fractions and solving one by one the pairs of simple division.</string>
    <string name="explicacion">Explanation</string>
    <string name="explicacion_detallada">Detailed</string>
    <string name="explicacion_no_detallada">Simple</string>
    <string name="FR_CAI_DEN_EXA">We will establish 1 as the denominator of the fraction</string>
    <string name="FR_CAI_IND">Change to an improper fraction the following fraction:</string>
    <string name="FR_CAI_SX_DES">A fraction that is expressed as a whole number plus a fractional part is a mixed fraction. The whole number of the mixed fraction can be added to its fractional part to change this mixed fraction to an improper fraction.</string>
    <string name="FR_CAI_SX_OPE">The numerator of the improper fraction is the result of the whole number of the mixed fraction multiplied by the denominator of its fractional part plus the numerator of the fractional part. The whole number is eliminated and the denominator remains the same.</string>
    <string name="FR_CAM_IND">Change to a mixed number, the following fraction:</string>
    <string name="FR_CAM_NOIMP">This fraction is not improper, therefore, it can not be changed to a mixed fraction.</string>
    <string name="FR_CAM_NOMIX">This is not a mixed fraction, it can not be converted.</string>
    <string name="FR_CAM_NOSIMP">This fraction is not an improper fraction nor reducible, it can not be simplified.</string>
    <string name="FR_CAM_SX_CII_EXA">In some fractions, there will be an exact and complete division where the result will be only a whole number and it can be proved using the following operation:</string>
    <string name="FR_CAM_SX_CIII_ENT">The whole number of the mixed fraction will be added to the whole number of another mixed fraction.</string>
    <string name="FR_CAM_SX_CIII_MIX">But if the fraction is a mixed fraction, we will only deal with the fractional part of the mixed fraction.</string>
    <string name="FR_CAM_SX_DES">A fraction where the numerator is bigger than the denominator is improper. This means that it contains a whole number that can be extracted and from there a mixed number or mixed fraction can be obtained.</string>
    <string name="FR_CAM_SX_DET_DEN">Finally, the denominator of the mixed fraction will remain the same.</string>
    <string name="FR_CAM_SX_DET_ENT">The whole number results from dividing the numerator by the denominator plus a fraction.</string>
    <string name="FR_CAM_SX_DET_NUM">The numerator of the mixed fraction results from multiplying the whole number by the denominator and subtracting the result from the numerator of the original fraction;</string>
    <string name="FR_RESULTADO">What we end up with as the final result: </string>
    <string name="FR_SIM_IND">Simplify the following fraction:</string>
    <string name="FR_SIM_MCD">We must find the maximum common divisor (MCD) where we can divide the numerator and the denominator by this number, evenly.</string>
    <string name="FR_SIM_SX_CAM">Comparing the numerator with the denominator where the numerator is a bigger number, this fraction is an improper fraction and it can be converted to a mixed fraction.</string>
    <string name="FR_SIM_SX_DIV">Finally, we divide the numerator and the denominator by the MCD that we have just calculated.</string>
    <string name="FR_SIM_SX_INT">To simplify a fraction means to reduce it to a more simple fraction.</string>
    <string name="FR_SIM_SX_UNI_MIX">As the numerator and denominator are the same, the fractional part has a value of 1, so it only add to the value of the whole part.</string>
    <string name="FR_SIM_SX_UNI_NOMIX">A fraction in which the numerator and denominator are equal, is called fraction unit, so its value is 1.</string>
    <string name="FUN_CAI_FRACS_RES">Fractions are as follows after conversion.</string>
    <string name="FUN_DET_EQU">It will be determined if the following fractions are equivalent.</string>
    <string name="FUN_DET_MAY">It will be determined which one of the following fractions is the biggest:</string>
    <string name="FUN_DET_REC">It will be determined if the following fractions are reciprocal:</string>
    <string name="FUN_INST_EQU">Two fractions are equivalent if the products of the numerator of one fraction by the denominator of the other fraction are equal.</string>
    <string name="FUN_INST_MAY">To find out which of the fractions is bigger we multiply the numerator of one fraction by the denominator of the other and in these multiplications, which will be two of them, from the resulting multiplications, the one with the biggest value, its first multiplier will be the numerator of the biggest fraction that we are finding.</string>
    <string name="FUN_INST_REC">Two fractions are reciprocal if the product of their numerators is equal to the product of their denominators.</string>
    <string name="FUN_PLT">Therefore:</string>
    <string name="FUN_RES_IGU">The fractions are equal</string>
    <string name="FUN_RES_MAY">The biggest is:</string>
    <string name="FUN_RES_NO_EQU">The fractions are not equivalent.</string>
    <string name="FUN_RES_NO_REC">The fractions are not reciprocal.</string>
    <string name="FUN_RES_SI_EQU">The fractions are equivalent.</string>
    <string name="FUN_RES_SI_REC">The fractions are reciprocal.</string>
    <string name="idioma">Language</string>
    <string name="idioma_espanol">Spanish</string>
    <string name="idioma_ingles">English</string>
    <string name="mensaje_cambio_explicacion">The changes in the level of detail of the explanation will be shown the next time that an operation is solved.</string>
    <string name="mensaje_cambio_idioma">The language will change the next time you open the application</string>
    <string name="MIX_NX_GRUP">The multiplications and divisions are grouped and then they are solved:</string>
    <string name="MIX_NX_SUMRES">The additions and subtractions are solved:</string>
    <string name="MIX_SX_GRUP">When we have an operation where there is a combination of additions or subtractions with multiplications or divisions, change the order of the sequence of the operation. First solve the multiplications and divisions and finally the additions and subtractions. What we will do is group the operations in that way:</string>
    <string name="MIX_SX_PAREN">We first solve the operations that are inside the parenthesis:</string>
    <string name="MIX_SX_SUMRES">At the end, we solved the remaining additions and subtractions: </string>
    <string name="MUL_DIV_NX_GRUP">The first fraction is grouped with the multiplications and then solved, afterwards the divisions are solved.</string>
    <string name="MUL_DIV_SX_GRUP">To solve an operation where we have multiplications and divisions together, we first group the first fraction with the other fractions that will be multiplied; after we have this result, we divide this result by the next fraction and then we divide this result by the following fraction and continue this process until we finish with the divisions.</string>
    <string name="MUL_NX">The numerators are multiplied as indicated, and the same with the denominators:</string>
    <string name="MUL_SX">The numerator of the final result of the multiplication of fractions is equal to the product of the numerators, and at the same time, the denominator is equal to the product of the denominators:</string>
    <string name="OPE_EMP_ESM">This fraction is a mixed fraction:</string>
    <string name="OPE_INI">The following operation will be resolved:</string>
    <string name="OPE_NX_CAI">We convert the mixed fractions to improper fractions:</string>
    <string name="OPE_NX_RES_SIM">The simplified fraction is:</string>
    <string name="OPE_RES">The result of the operation is:</string>
    <string name="OPE_RES_CONV">The operation is performed like this:</string>
    <string name="OPE_SX_CAI">The carry out resolve the operation we first have to convert all of the mixed fractions to improper fractions:</string>
    <string name="OPE_SX_EMP_CAI">To begin with the operation, all of the fractions must be represented in the same form, converting the fractions that are mixed fractions into improper fractions.</string>
    <string name="resumen_explicacion"> Choose the type of explanation for operations procedures</string>
    <string name="resumen_idioma">Choose the language of the application</string>
    <string name="step">Step <xliff:g id="step_number">%1$d</xliff:g>:</string>
    <string name="step_calculos_descripcion">Calculate the least common multiple and Greatest Common Factor between various issues.</string>
    <string name="step_calculos_titulo">Auxiliary calculations</string>
    <string name="step_comparaciones_descripcion"> Make comparisons between fractions, such as determining if two fractions are equivalent, reciprocal or the largest of them.</string>
    <string name="step_comparaciones_titulo">Comparisons</string>
    <string name="step_conversiones_descripcion">Simplify fractions, convert improper fractions into mixed fractions and vice versa.</string>
    <string name="step_conversiones_titulo">Conversions</string>
    <string name="step_explicaciones_descripcion">Get step by step explanation of the solution of the operations you perform with FraccionApp.</string>
    <string name="step_explicaciones_titulo">Explanations</string>
    <string name="step_operaciones_descripcion"> Performs operations of addition, subtraction, multiplication and division of fractions.</string>
    <string name="step_operaciones_titulo">Basic operations</string>
    <string name="SUM_NX_DEN_DIF">We convert the fractions to equivalent fractions and they will have the same denominator:</string>
    <string name="SUM_NX_DEN_IGU">We perform the operations among the numerators:</string>
    <string name="SUM_SX_CONV_MCM">The numerator of each new fraction is equal to dividing the lcm calculated by the denominator of the fraction and then multiplying this result by the numerator of the fraction, the denominator of the new fraction will be the lcm.</string>
    <string name="SUM_SX_DEN">In the addition or subtraction of fractions, first we should analyze the denominators:</string>
    <string name="SUM_SX_DEN_DIF">When the denominators are different, we should express the fractions in such a form that they have the same denominator. To do this we calculate the least common multiple.</string>
    <string name="SUM_SX_DEN_IGU">When the denominators are equal, the operation is resolved directly, adding or subtracting the numerators as appropriate to the operation, and the denominator remains the same.</string>
    <string name="SUM_SX_OPE_NUMS">Finally, the operations among the numerators will be performed:</string>
    <string name="title_activity_calculadora">Calculator</string>
    <string name="title_activity_configuracion">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_first_steps">First steps</string>
    <string name="titulo_cai">Convert mixed fraction into improper fraction</string>
    <string name="titulo_cam">Convert improper fraction into mixed fraction</string>
    <string name="titulo_equivalentes">Equivalent fractions</string>
    <string name="titulo_mayor"> The largest of two fractions.</string>
    <string name="titulo_mcd">Greatest common divisor</string>
    <string name="titulo_mcm">Least common multiple</string>
    <string name="titulo_reciprocas">Reciprocal fractions</string>
    <string name="titulo_simplificar">Simplify fraction</string>
</resources>